Bulut Karakaya

bulutk@gmail.com | www.bulutk.com

Phone: +44 (7470) 890039 | Skype: bulutkarakaya

Career Objective

Oct 2020

I'm an ambitious gameplay programmer with 12+ years of experience. My focus areas are core gameplay and networking using Unity and Unreal engines. I co-founded two indie game studios before and currently working to create inspiring games in the UK. My inspiration is to find ways to merge my interest in machine learning with game development to open new possibilities.

Work Experience	I ID (C III
March 2021 - Present	Lead Programmer – ustwo Games, U.K. • Technical lead on Desta: The Memories Between.
	• Line manager for 3 senior and a junior programmer.
T 1 2010 N 1 2021	
July 2018 - March 2021 March 2017 - June 2018	Senior Gameplay Programmer – Jagex Ltd, Cambridge, U.K.
	 Worked on an unannounced Action-RPG game using Unreal Engine 4, C++. Worked on core combat, player and AI navigation as well as high-level networking.
	Lead Unity Programmer – Digit Game Studio, Dublin, Ireland
March 2017 - June 2018 Oct 2016 - March 2017	• Worked on Star Trek: Fleet Command, for IOS and Android using Unity, C#
	• Line manager for a senior and a mid-level programmer.
	Senior Unity Programmer – Digit Game Studio, Dublin, Ireland
	• Worked on Star Trek: Fleet Command, for IOS and Android using Unity, C#
Nov 2014 - May 2016	Co-founder / Technical Director – Pera Games, Istanbul, Turkey
100 2014 - May 2010	• Created Overfall a rogue-like RPG title for Steam using Unity, C#
	• Responsible for all the programming and creating the tools for our non-technical team to create characters, spells
	environments and encounters without programmer help.
	• Launched the game on Steam, %93 positive feedback at the end of the first month.
	 Presented Overfall at Unite'16 as a showcase game.
March 2014 - Sept 2014	Project Partner – GriPati Digital Entertainment, Istanbul, Turkey
March 2014 Sept 2014	• Created Egg Fight a multiplayer fast-paced fighting game for IOS and Android using Unity, C#
	• Responsible for all the programming and partial game design.
Jan 2013 - Feb 2014	Co-founder / Technical Director – Tart Games, Istanbul, Turkey
	• Created Kixel a multiplayer 3d soccer game for Facebook and IOS using Unity, C#
	• Responsible for most of the gameplay programming and leading a team of 6 people.
Aug 2012 - April 2013	Software Engineer – Tart New Media, Istanbul, Turkey
	• Responsible for optimising and developing the backend of gamification engine.
	• Line manager for 2 junior programmers.
Sept 2010 - Dec 2011	Gameplay Programmer – Gravi, Istanbul, Turkey
	• Worked on Gravi Floor, an interactive playground which features various mini-games.
June 2009 - Aug 2009	Prototype Intern – Stupid Fun Club, Berkeley, USA
	• Stupid Fun Club is an entertainment think tank company created by Will Wright
	• Worked on prototypes for unannounced projects using C# and XNA.
July 2007 - Sept 2007	Internship – Microsoft Corporation, Redmond, USA
	• The First intern accepted to US office from a Turkish university.
Education	·
May 2010 May 2008	Carnegie Mellon University (CMU) - Entertainment Technologies Center, Pittsburgh, U.S.A
	• Master Of Entertainment Technology (MET)
	• Created SurfaceScapes, a D&D experience on Microsoft Surface table. Presented in GDC'10 and PAX East.
	• TA for Building Virtual Worlds course.
	Sabanci University (SU), Istanbul, Turkey
	 Bachelor of Science degree in Computer Science and Engineering (CS) TA for VA433 3D Modeling and VA434 3D Animation course.
Certificates	
	M 1' T ' C' 6 1TI' '4 (C)
Aug 2020	Machine Learning - Stanford University (Coursera)
Oct 2020	Neural Networks and Deep Learning - DeepLearning.AI (Coursera)

Improving Deep Neural Networks - DeepLearning.AI (Coursera)

Bulut Karakaya – bulutk@gmail.com

Skills

Proficient: C#, C++

Engines & Libraries: Unity, Unreal Engine 4

Version Control: Git, Perforce

Language: English (fluent), Turkish (Native)

Others: Maya, AfterEffects, PhotoShop (for programmer art)

Interests

Certified diver, tango dancer, Wing-Tsun practitioner, snowboarder and aerial acrobat. I also like games (\underline{Link}) and reading (\underline{Link}).